Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
My name is Catherine and today we have a special dialogue for you all about this important
我是Catherine，今天我们有一个特别的对话，关于这个重要的
test that you need for going to graduate school.
读研究生需要的考试。
That's right.
没错。
Today we're going to talk about the famous or very scary GMAT.
今天我们要聊聊那个著名或者说很吓人的GMAT考试。
Alright so the GMAT, G-M-A-T, is the test that students will take when they want to
好的，GMAT，G-M-A-T，是学生想读
go to graduate school for business management, so an MBA program.
商科研究生（MBA项目）时要参加的考试。
That's right.
没错。
It's pretty much a standard test that you have to take, as you say, to get into one
这基本上是一个标准考试，就像你说的，要进入
of these programs.
这些项目就必须考。
Today, we're going to talk a little bit about the sections of the test and more or less
今天，我们会简单聊聊考试的各个部分以及
how it's structured, but not too much in depth.
它的结构，但不会太深入。
That's right.
没错。
Let's take a listen to our dialogue.
我们来听听对话吧。
We'll be back in a moment.
我们一会儿回来。
I can't seem to progress up the career ladder no matter how hard I try.
不管我怎么努力，似乎都没法在职业阶梯上往上爬。
And I have been here for two years already.
而且我已经在这里待了两年了。
Well, have you thought of getting an MBA?
嗯，你有没有想过读个MBA？
I heard it does wonders in getting you to the top.
我听说它对升到高层有奇效。
An MBA, hey?
MBA，是吗？
Well, my degree wasn't in business.
嗯，我的学位不是商科的。
The business schools won't be interested in me.
商学院不会对我感兴趣的。
Nonsense.
胡说。
The business schools measure your ability through a test called GMAT.
商学院通过一个叫GMAT的考试来衡量你的能力。
GMAT?
GMAT？
What does that stand for and what will the test contain?
它代表什么，考试会包含什么内容？
Graduate Management Admission Test.
研究生管理科入学考试。
It contains three parts, analytical writing assessment, the quantitative section, and
它包含三个部分：分析性写作评估、数学部分
the verbal section.
和语文部分。
Not only does the test score you on the number of questions answered, but also on the difficulty.
这个考试不仅根据你答对的数量评分，还根据难度评分。
Okay, this sounds a little tough.
好吧，这听起来有点难。
How am I supposed to practice for this?
我该怎么练习呢？
Up to you.
随你便。
You could have a one-on-one session with a tutor or group sessions.
你可以和导师一对一上课，或者参加小组课程。
You can also use free or private computer software.
你也可以用免费或付费的电脑软件。
Going to church might help as well.
去教堂祈祷可能也有帮助。
No matter what I do, I'm going to ace this test and go on to become a corporate fat cat.
不管我做什么，我都要考好这个试，然后成为企业大亨。
That's the spirit.
这才像话。
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So now let's talk about some of the language we found on Language Takeaway.
现在我们来聊聊在“语言点”部分发现的一些语言点。
Language Takeaway.
语言点。
All right, so there's a lot of great stuff here.
好的，这里有很多好东西。
The first one we've got is actually more about a job than school.
第一个其实更多是关于工作而不是学校。
This is the career ladder.
这是“职业阶梯”。
That's right, Ash is complaining how he can't seem to make any progress in the career ladder.
没错，Ash在抱怨他似乎在职业阶梯上无法进步。
So what is a career ladder?
那么什么是职业阶梯？
We know what a ladder is.
我们知道梯子是什么。
A ladder is a tool that you use to climb from a low place to a high place.
梯子是一种工具，用来从低处爬到高处。
So for example, if you want to go on the roof of your house, you have to use a ladder.
比如，如果你想上屋顶，就得用梯子。
A career ladder is like an analogy.
职业阶梯是一个比喻。
When you start a career, you start at the bottom and you climb up, up, up to the top.
当你开始职业生涯时，你从底层开始，然后一步步往上爬，直到顶层。
So going from the bottom to maybe the president of an organization.
所以从底层爬到可能成为组织总裁的位置。
So that's called the career ladder.
这就叫职业阶梯。
Yeah, climbing from the bottom of a career area, like for example, being the mailman
是啊，从职业领域的底层爬起，比如在办公楼里当邮递员
at an office building to being the president of that office.
到成为那栋楼的总裁。
Okay, so this is what Ash is complaining about, that it's hard or he can't really seem to
好的，这就是Ash在抱怨的，他很难或者似乎无法
go up the career ladder.
在职业阶梯上往上爬。
And so Mindy suggests that he should take the GMAT and go into graduate school.
然后Mindy建议他应该考GMAT，去读研究生。
So as we said, the GMAT is a test that you take, but what does it stand for?
就像我们说的，GMAT是一个要参加的考试，但它代表什么？
What is GMAT?
GMAT是什么？
GMAT stands for Graduate Management Admission Test.
GMAT代表研究生管理科入学考试。
Okay, so that's the test that you take when you want to go to school.
好的，所以这是你想上学时要参加的考试。
So you have to send your scores to the admissions office of the school you want to go to and
你得把你的成绩寄给你想去的学校的招生办公室，
they will decide if they're high enough or not.
他们会决定成绩是否足够高。
Okay, very good.
好的，很好。
So not everyone can go to graduate school and you have to take this test and pass it
所以不是每个人都能读研究生，你基本上得参加这个考试并通过它。
basically.
基本上是这样。
So there's no pass fail, but certain schools will say that a score is high enough and other
但考试没有及格或不及格之分，某些学校会说某个分数够了，
schools will say that a higher score is more important.
而其他学校会说更高的分数更重要。
So you can maybe go to a better school if you have a better score.
所以如果你分数更高，也许能上更好的学校。
Okay, and well, Mindy went on to explain the three parts of this test.
好的，然后Mindy继续解释了考试的三个部分。
The first one she said is analytical writing.
她说的第一个是分析性写作。
All right, so analytical writing is a very common part of a test.
好的，分析性写作是考试中很常见的一部分。
For example, I think the SAT also has analytical writing and basically you're asked to read
比如，我觉得SAT也有分析性写作，基本上你要读
something and then write about it.
一些东西然后写出来。
And analytical means that you have to really use your mind to make an argument.
分析性意味着你必须真正动脑来提出论点。
It's not just read and repeat, read and repeat.
不只是读和重复，读和重复。
So basically it comes from analyzing.
所以基本上它来自“分析”。
You analyze what you read and then you write about it.
你分析你读到的内容，然后写出来。
That's right.
没错。
You have to think and you have to understand what you read and then you have to write something
你必须思考，理解你读的内容，然后写点什么，
that makes sense.
而且要有意义。
It's logical.
这很合乎逻辑。
Do you put your opinion in analytical writing?
在分析性写作中，你会加入自己的观点吗？
No.
不会。
So it's all based on facts.
所以这完全基于事实。
Based on facts and logic and argument.
基于事实、逻辑和论证。
Uh-huh, okay.
嗯哼，好的。
So you have this part of analytical writing.
所以这是分析性写作的部分。
And then Mindy talks about the quantitative section of the test.
然后明迪谈到了考试的定量部分。
So what is this?
那这是什么？
So the quantitative section, you think of the word quantify, quantity, quantitative
定量部分，你想到“量化”、“数量”、“定量的”这些词，
has to do with numbers.
和数字有关。
Math, basically.
基本上就是数学。
So you have to be able to understand basic math, some algebra, some arithmetic, some
所以你必须理解基础数学、一些代数、一些算术、一些
statistics for example.
统计学，比如。
So quantitative sections on tests are the math sections.
所以考试中的定量部分就是数学部分。
Now from my understanding, even though it is a math section, it's not really like they
据我理解，虽然这是数学部分，但并不是直接
give you a problem, an equation and you have to solve it.
给你一个题目、一个方程让你解。
It's more like analysis, right?
更像是分析，对吧？
They give you some information and you have to use math to solve it.
他们给你一些信息，你需要用数学来解决。
That's right.
没错。
So there are a number of different parts.
所以有好几个不同的部分。
One of them is like what you say.
其中一部分就像你说的那样。
It's kind of a, it's about logic while using algebra to solve these problems.
有点像，是关于用代数解决这些问题的逻辑。
I think the other part of it has to do with statistics and being able to understand trends,
我觉得另一部分和统计学有关，要能理解趋势、
graphs, things like that.
图表之类的东西。
So this is the math section of the exam.
所以这是考试的数学部分。
So not only do you have to be able to read, understand and analyze what you're reading,
所以你不仅要能阅读、理解和分析你读的内容，
you have to be able to be good at math.
还得擅长数学。
And then finally we have a verbal section.
最后我们还有语文部分。
What is this all about?
这主要是关于什么的？
This is about your English language and grammar skills.
这是关于你的英语语言和语法技能。
So the verbal section will test your vocabulary knowledge.
所以语文部分会测试你的词汇知识。
Do you understand what big words mean?
你理解那些大词的意思吗？
Also will test your ability to read passages and analyze them.
还会测试你阅读文章并分析它们的能力。
So I guess this part is the most important, one of the most important parts for foreign
所以我想这部分对于母语不是英语的外国学生来说是最重要的部分之一。
students who obviously don't speak English as their first language.
This makes sure that you have a good enough English level to be able to take a graduate
这确保你有足够好的英语水平，能够用英语攻读研究生
program in English, right?
项目，对吧？
Part of it's that there's a special test that will test your English abilities, but this
有一部分是，有一个专门的考试会测试你的英语能力，但这
is absolutely an important part for a non-native English speaker on the GMAT.
对于非英语母语者来说，在GMAT中绝对是重要的一部分。
You have to, it's hard for English speakers who were born speaking English, you know,
你必须，这对母语是英语的人来说也很难，你知道，
natives English speakers.
以英语为母语的人。
Yeah.
是的。
So it's something that really you should devote your time to if you are a non-native English
所以如果你是非英语母语者，你真的应该花时间在这上面，
speaker because there will be some very challenging words there.
因为那里会有一些非常有挑战性的词汇。
Okay.
好的。
So those are the three sections of the GMAT.
所以这就是GMAT的三个部分。
And so to finish off language takeaway, Ash said that he's going to take this test because
为了结束语言点部分，阿什说他要去考这个试，因为
he wants to become a corporate fat cat.
他想成为一个企业大亨。
All right.
好的。
Now this is an interesting term.
现在这是一个有趣的术语。
This is not something we talk about in the office.
这不是我们在办公室谈论的东西。
This is something we talk about with friends.
这是和朋友聊天时说的。
So corporate fat cat, you think corporate, corporation, this has to do with business.
所以“企业大亨”，你想到“企业”、“公司”，这和商业有关。
So basically we're talking about very important businessmen, but fat cat's not a good thing,
所以基本上我们说的是非常重要的商人，但“大亨”不是个好词，
right?
对吧？
No, it's not really.
不，确实不是。
You refer to a fat cat, a corporate fat cat, as a businessman who you consider to have
你称一个人为“大亨”或“企业大亨”，是指你认为他
a lot of money, but obviously you make the analogy that they're fat because they have
很有钱，但显然你拿他们和“胖”做类比，因为他们有
so much money.
那么多钱。
And it's kind of a way of saying that businessmen are not the, corporate fat cats are not the
这有点像在说商人不是，企业大亨不是
best people around.
最好的人。
No, you're basically saying that these guys, these men on top, they're rich, but they're
不，你基本上是在说这些家伙，这些顶层的人，他们有钱，但
kind of lazy.
有点懒。
And so he wants to be a corporate fat cat.
所以他想成为一个企业大亨。
He wants to be very rich and powerful and not have to work so hard.
他想变得非常有钱有势，不用那么辛苦工作。
Which obviously is not really the case always, but this is a common term that, as you said,
这显然不总是事实，但这是一个常见的术语，就像你说的，
you wouldn't really mention it in the office, but it's more of a satirical way of describing
你不会在办公室提到它，但它更像是一种讽刺的方式
speaking about businessmen.
来描述商人。
All right, so now let's finish off language takeaway and move on to some phrases on Fluency
好的，现在让我们结束语言点部分，进入流利度
Builder.
构建者的一些短语。
I can't seem to progress up the career ladder no matter how hard I try.
无论我怎么努力，似乎都无法在职业阶梯上往上爬。
And I have been here for two years already.
而且我已经在这里待了两年了。
Well, have you thought of getting an MBA?
嗯，你有没有考虑过读MBA？
I heard it does wonders in getting you to the top.
我听说它对让你达到顶峰有奇效。
An MBA, hey?
MBA，是吗？
Well, my degree wasn't in business.
嗯，我的学位不是商科的。
The business schools won't be interested in me.
商学院不会对我感兴趣的。
Nonsense.
胡说。
The business schools measure your ability through a test called GMAT.
商学院通过一项叫GMAT的考试来衡量你的能力。
GMAT?
GMAT？
What does that stand for and what will the test contain?
它代表什么，考试内容又是什么？
Graduate Management Admission Test.
研究生管理科入学考试。
It contains three parts, analytical writing assessment, the quantitative section, and
它包含三个部分：分析性写作评估、数学部分和
the verbal section.
语文部分。
Not only does the test score you on the number of questions answered, but also on the difficulty.
考试不仅根据你回答的问题数量评分，还根据难度评分。
Okay, this sounds a little tough.
好吧，这听起来有点难。
How am I supposed to practice for this?
我该怎么准备这个？
Up to you.
取决于你。
You could have a one-on-one session with a tutor or group sessions.
你可以和导师一对一上课，或者参加小组课程。
You can also use free or private computer software.
你也可以使用免费或私人的电脑软件。
Going to church might help as well.
去教堂祈祷也许也有帮助。
No matter what I do, I'm going to ace this test and go on to become a corporate fat cat.
不管我做什么，我都要考好这个试，然后成为企业大亨。
That's the spirit.
这才像话。
All right, in Fluency Builder today we have a number of really great phrases you can use.
好了，在今天的流利度训练中，我们有很多很棒的短语可以用。
The first one is from Mindy.
第一个来自Mindy。
She says, I heard it does wonders in getting you to the top.
她说，我听说它对让你达到顶峰有奇效。
Right.
对。
She suggests getting an MBA.
她建议读MBA。
I heard it does wonders to improve your career.
我听说它对提升你的职业有奇效。
This is actually something that you might hear in a commercial.
这其实是你可能在广告中听到的话。
It does wonders means it really helps.
“有奇效”意思是它真的很有帮助。
It's really beneficial to you.
它对你非常有益。
You might hear it in a commercial, for example, with a face cream.
你可能会在广告中听到，比如面霜广告。
It does wonders to your skin.
它对你的皮肤有奇效。
It really makes your skin look good.
它真的让你的皮肤看起来很好。
By using this phrase, it does wonders, you're basically saying it's fast, it's effective,
使用这个短语“有奇效”，你基本上是在说它快速、有效，
it's almost a miracle of how much it can improve your career or in this case of the cream,
它几乎是个奇迹，能如此提升你的职业，或者在这个面霜的例子中，
how it can improve your face.
它能如此改善你的脸。
That's right.
没错。
The MBA does wonders.
MBA有奇效。
It's almost miraculous how positive and effective it will have on your career.
它对你的职业产生的积极和有效影响几乎是奇迹般的。
Exactly.
正是。
Okay.
好的。
It does wonders.
有奇效。
Then Ash was asking how he's supposed to study for this and Mindy answered, well, you know
然后Ash问他该怎么学习这个，Mindy回答说，嗯，你知道吗？
what?
你知道吗？
It's up to you.
取决于你。
You have a lot of options.
你有很多选择。
She said, up to you.
她说，“取决于你”。
Up to you.
取决于你。
This means it's your decision.
这意味着这是你的决定。
We can use this in normal life.
我们在日常生活中可以用这个。
You and I are out, Marco, and I say, well, I don't know what to eat.
你和我出去了，Marco，我说，嗯，我不知道吃什么。
What do you want to eat?
你想吃什么？
I can say, oh, whatever.
我可以说，哦，随便。
It's up to you.
取决于你。
Up to me.
取决于我。
That means I get to decide what we eat and I want pizza.
这意味着我来决定我们吃什么，我要吃披萨。
Okay.
好的。
Very good.
很好。
All right.
好了。
Up to you is a way to say, no, you decide.
“取决于你”是一种说“不，你决定”的方式。
It's up to you.
取决于你。
It's your decision.
这是你的决定。
Okay.
好的。
For our next phrase, Ash was saying that he's going to study really hard and he's going
对于下一个短语，Ash说他将努力学习，并且他会
to ace the test.
考好这个试。
All right.
好了。
Now, to ace a test, this is a phrase that we use.
现在，“考好一个试”，这是我们用的一个短语。
We can use it in high school and college as well, not just MBA programs.
我们可以在高中和大学也用，不只是MBA课程。
To ace a test means to do perfectly on it.
“考好一个试”意思是完美地完成它。
That means to get an A or even 100%.
这意味着得A甚至100分。
It's important to remember that we have this grading system, A, B, C, D, F. A is the top.
重要的是要记住我们有这个评分系统，A、B、C、D、F。A是最高分。
You ace it means you don't make any mistakes.
“考好”意味着你没有犯任何错误。
Remember that, A for ace.
记住，A代表ace（王牌）。
Okay.
好的。
You can even use it if it's not really a test.
你甚至可以在不是考试的情况下用它。
Like a job interview, you say, I aced that job interview.
比如工作面试，你说，我那次工作面试表现完美。
I ace it.
我表现完美。
In sports, oftentimes, we see this tennis.
在体育中，我们经常看到这个，比如网球。
It's a sports analogy.
这是一个体育类比。
Tennis, when someone serves a ball and the other player can't even hit the ball back,
网球中，当有人发球而另一个球员甚至无法把球打回来，
it's an ace.
那就是一个ace球。
You get a point.
你得分。
That's right.
没错。
It's an ace for that.
那是一个ace球。
Even good sports athletes, you call them aces.
即使是优秀的体育运动员，你也会称他们为“王牌”。
After a job interview, I can say, wow, Marco, I really aced that interview.
面试结束后，我可以说，哇，马可，我面试真的表现得超棒。
I aced it.
我搞定了。
That's right.
没错。
Mindy says, well, you know what?
明迪说，嗯，你知道吗？
That's really good.
那真不错。
That's the spirit.
这才像话。
Now, this is something you say to someone when you like their attitude.
这句话是你喜欢某人态度时说的。
If I say, oh man, I did really bad.
如果我说，哦，天哪，我做得真差。
This is stupid.
这太蠢了。
I don't want to study.
我不想学习。
You say, well, that's a bad attitude.
你会说，嗯，那态度可不好。
If I say, you know what?
如果我说，你知道吗？
I'm going to do awesome.
我会做得超棒。
This is great.
这太棒了。
I'm going to kill this.
我要大干一场。
I'm going to ace it.
我要搞定它。
You can say, that's the spirit.
你可以说，这才像话。
That's the spirit.
这才像话。
That means good attitude.
意思是态度好。
That's the right way to think about this.
这是正确的思考方式。
So you're kind of even encouraging that person.
所以你甚至是在鼓励那个人。
You're saying, you know what?
你在说，你知道吗？
I really like your attitude.
我真的很喜欢你的态度。
That's the good way of thinking.
这是好的思维方式。
Exactly.
没错。
So if you want to push someone and say, good for you.
所以如果你想鼓励某人，说“好样的”。
This is a good way to approach it.
这是个好方法。
You say, that's the spirit.
你说，这才像话。
Okay.
好的。
Awesome.
太棒了。
So this is all the language that we have for Fluency Builder.
这就是我们“流利度构建”部分的所有语言点。
Why don't we take a break and we'll be right back.
我们休息一下，马上回来。
I can't seem to progress up the career ladder no matter how hard I try.
不管我怎么努力，似乎都无法在职业阶梯上进步。
And I have been here for two years already.
而且我已经在这里待了两年了。
Well, have you thought of getting an MBA?
嗯，你有没有考虑过读个MBA？
I heard it does wonders in getting you to the top.
我听说它对升职有奇效。
An MBA, hey?
MBA，是吗？
Well, my degree wasn't in business.
嗯，我的学位不是商科的。
The business schools won't be interested in me.
商学院不会对我感兴趣的。
Nonsense.
胡说。
The business schools measure your ability through a test called GMAT.
商学院通过一个叫GMAT的考试来衡量你的能力。
GMAT?
GMAT？
What does that stand for?
那代表什么？
And what will the test contain?
考试会包含什么内容？
Graduate Management Admission Test.
研究生管理入学考试。
It contains three parts.
它包含三个部分。
Analytical Writing Assessment, the Quantitative Section, and the Verbal Section.
分析性写作评估、定量部分和语文部分。
Not only does the test score you on the number of questions answered, but also on the difficulty.
考试不仅根据你回答的问题数量评分，还根据难度评分。
Okay, this sounds a little tough.
好吧，这听起来有点难。
How am I supposed to practice for this?
我该怎么练习这个？
Up to you.
随你便。
You could have a one-on-one session with a tutor or group sessions.
你可以和导师一对一上课，或者参加小组课程。
You can also use free or private computer software.
你也可以使用免费或付费的电脑软件。
Going to church might help as well.
去教堂祈祷可能也有帮助。
No matter what I do, I'm going to ace this test and go on to become a corporate fat cat.
不管我做什么，我都要考好这个试，然后成为企业里的肥猫。
That's the spirit.
这才像话。
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So now talking about the GMAT and an MBA.
现在来谈谈GMAT和MBA。
This seems to be a very popular topic nowadays.
这似乎是现在很热门的话题。
Everyone wants to get obviously a good education and go to graduate school, which means getting
每个人都想接受良好的教育，去读研究生，也就是拿到硕士学位或博士学位。
your master's degree or your doctoral degree.
你对GMAT和MBA怎么看？
What do you think about the GMAT and the MBA?
它是不是像这个女孩说的那样是个奇迹？
Is it a miracle worker like this girl says she does?
哇，它对职业有奇效。
Wow, it does wonders for your career.
你觉得真的是这样吗？
Do you think that's really the case?
我不知道。
I don't know.
也许如果你五年前问我，我会说是的。
Maybe if you asked me five years ago, I would say yes.
但我真的相信这取决于个人。
But I really believe that it depends on the person.
没有什么灵丹妙药。
Nothing is a miracle cure.
我确实认为，如果你态度好、努力，你会从中收获很多。
I do think that if you really have a good attitude and you work hard, you'll get a lot
但如果你认为它能帮你找到工作，那你就错了，因为你需要自己去找工作。
out of it.
所以我认为这取决于个人。
But if you think it's going to get you a job, you're wrong because you have to get yourself
现在显然也取决于国家，对吧？
a job.
在美国，比如说，拥有MBA对在商界取得成功有多流行或多重要？
So I think it depends on the person.
我觉得挺重要的。
Now obviously also it depends on the country, right?
现在显然也取决于国家，对吧？
Now how popular or how important is it for people to have, let's say, an MBA to get ahead
在美国，比如说，拥有MBA对在商界取得成功有多流行或多重要？
in business in the United States?
我觉得挺重要的。
I'd say it's pretty important.
我会说这相当重要。
You don't have to have an MBA.
你不一定非得有MBA学位。
I mean, you can start your own business.
我的意思是，你可以自己创业。
And if you're successful, you'll probably start more businesses.
如果你成功了，你可能会创办更多企业。
But getting an MBA is also a very good opportunity to network, to meet people, to find out more
但读MBA也是一个很好的机会，可以拓展人脉、结识朋友、了解更多
about the industry that you want to start out in.
关于你想进入的行业的信息。
And so I think in that sense, it's pretty important because it's a way to start making
所以从这个角度来说，我认为它挺重要的，因为这是开始建立
contacts.
人脉的一种方式。
Yeah, you definitely meet a lot of people with work experience from different backgrounds,
是啊，你肯定会遇到很多来自不同背景、有工作经验的人，
international students.
还有国际学生。
So it's obviously a great thing.
所以这显然是一件好事。
But obviously to be able to do one of these programs, like get an MBA, you have to take
但显然，要参加这类项目，比如读MBA，你必须通过
these tests, which I understand are very, very difficult.
这些考试，我知道这些考试非常非常难。
They are very difficult and it can be very expensive.
它们确实很难，而且费用可能非常昂贵。
I mean, graduate school itself is $100,000, $200,000.
我是说，研究生院本身就要花10万、20万美元。
And then to prepare for the tests, you could spend another $1,000 just getting classes
然后为了准备考试，你可能还要再花1000美元去上课
or tutoring.
或请家教。
So I do think that it can be a lot of money up front.
所以我认为前期投入确实很大。
But there are places that you can go to study and you could even study on your own using
但也有一些地方可以学习，你甚至可以用电脑
your computer.
自学。
Yeah, exactly.
是的，没错。
I think this is a very interesting topic because in many different cultures, in many different
我觉得这个话题很有趣，因为在许多不同的文化、许多不同的
places, education or, for example, higher learning, like getting an MBA, has different
地方，教育或比如高等教育，像读MBA，有着不同的
levels of importance.
重要性。
Like in Europe, a lot of Europeans maybe don't really even pay too much attention to getting
比如在欧洲，很多欧洲人可能不太重视
an MBA.
读MBA。
Whereas in other countries, they might really emphasize like you have to have an MBA.
而在其他国家，他们可能非常强调你必须要有MBA学位。
It's really good.
这真的很好。
It's really good for your career.
对你的职业发展真的很有好处。
So it's very interesting to see how in different places they handle it.
所以看到不同地方如何处理这件事，非常有趣。
It is interesting.
确实很有趣。
And I'm actually very curious to hear from our users.
我其实很想知道我们用户的看法。
Have you ever thought about getting an MBA?
你有没有想过读MBA？
Are MBAs important to do business in your country?
在你们国家，MBA对做生意重要吗？
Let us know.
告诉我们吧。
Our website is EnglishPod.com.
我们的网站是EnglishPod.com。
All right.
好了。
We'll see you guys there.
我们到时候见。
Bye.
再见。
Thank you.
谢谢。